Finding Aid for Michigan Today records, 1968-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Today records 1968-2007
Michigan Today
49025 Bimu 2
Alumni magazine currently published by the University of Michigan News Services. Records include complete run of the print publication, selected online issues, and photographs collected in preparation for publication.
4 linear feet
143 digital files
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Michigan Today collection has been assembled through regular receipt of the publication and from transfer of records from the University of Michigan News Service (Donor no. 285 )
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Michigan Today was first published in 1968 as a four-page newspaper for faculty and staff. Originally, Michigan Today was published by the university office for development and external relations. In 1984, the media relations office (currently, University of Michigan News Service) assumed publication responsibilities and Michigan Today became a 24-page quarterly alumni magazine with a circulation of more than 400,000 University of Michigan alumni. In 1993, an electronic version of the print publication was created and published continuously through the 1990s and early 2000s. In 2003, the monthly electronic newsletter, the "NewsE," was also developed as an online accompaniment to the regular print publication. In the Fall of 2006, the last print edition of Michigan Today was published. The magazine now exists only as an online publication called simply, "Michigan Today." The electronic newsletter continues to be distributed.
The Michigan Today records (4 linear feet and digital files) date from 1968 to 2007 and will be received on an ongoing basis. These records constitute a full run of the publication, as well as additional materials documenting the photographic research process. There are four series in the collection: Michigan Today: Print Edition, Michigan Today: Online Edition, Photographs, and Michigan Today: NewsE.
The Michigan Today: Online Edition series consists of the digital files used to publish the magazine to the web. It contains selected issues from the early online version of Michigan Today (published from March 1993 to July 2007) and all issues of the current online version of Michigan Today. Beginning in 2001, unique content was created for the online version of Michigan Today. An "Alumnae/Alumni News" section was published exclusively in the online version of the magazine and a "Books" section was published with additional content in the online version of the publication. Also, the current online version of Michigan Today published from September 2007 is included in this series. This represents the primary version of Michigan Today still being published.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Periodicals.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae--Periodicals.; University of Michigan--Faculty--Periodicals.; University of Michigan--Students--Periodicals.
Subjects-Visual Material:
University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Sports.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan--Students.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; CD-ROMs.
- Michigan Today: Print Edition 1968-2006
  The Michigan Today: Print Edition series consists of a complete run of the print publication v.1 no.1 (December 1968) to v.38 no.3 (Fall 2006). Print copies of Michigan Today are available at the Bentley Historical Library and scanned versions are available as pdf files. The scanned issues are accessible through Deep Blue (University of Michigan's Institutional Repository). The contents list below provides links to individual issues. The Deep Blue interface also provides full text searching of the print edition of Michigan Today.
  - 1968-1969
    - Vol. 01 No. 01, 1968-12
    - Vol. 01 No. 02, 1969-Spring
    - Vol. 01 No. 03, 1969-Summer
    - Vol. 01 No. 04, 1969-Fall
    - Vol. 02 No. 01, 1969-Winter
  - 1970/71-1978/79
    - Vol. 02 No. 02, 1970-Spring
    - Vol. 02 No. 03, 1970-Summer
    - Vol. 02 No. 04, 1970-Fall
    - Vol. 03 No. 01, 1970-Winter
    - Vol. 03 No. 02, 1971-Spring
    - Vol. 03 No. 03, 1971-Summer
    - Vol. 03 No. 04, 1971-Fall
    - Vol. 04 No. 01, 1972-Winter
    - Vol. 04 No. 02, 1972-Spring
    - Vol. 04 No. 03, 1972-Summer
    - Vol. 04 No. 04, 1972-08
    - Vol. 05 No. 01, 1972-12
    - Vol. 05 No. 02, 1973-03
    - Vol. 05 No. 03, 1973-06
    - Vol. 05 No. 04, 1973-09
    - Vol. 06 No. 01, 1973-12
    - Vol. 06 No. 02, 1974-03
    - Vol. 06 No. 03, 1974-06
    - Vol. 06 No. 04, 1974-09
    - Vol. 07 No. 01, 1974-12
    - Vol. 07 No. 02, 1975-03
    - Vol. 07 No. 03, 1975-06
    - Vol. 07 No. 04, 1975-Fall
    - Vol. 08 No. 01, 1975-12
    - Vol. 08 No. 02, 1976-Spring
    - Vol. 08 No. 03, 1976-Summer
    - Vol. 08 No. 04, 1976-Fall
    - Vol. 09 No. 01, 1977-Winter
    - Vol. 09 No. 02, 1977-Summer
    - Vol. 09 No. 03, 1977-Fall
    - Vol. 10 No. 01, 1977-78-Winter Term
    - Vol. 10 No. 02, 1978-Spring
    - Vol. 10 No. 03, 1978-Summer
    - Vol. 10 No. 04, 1978-Fall
    - Vol. 11 No. 01, 1978-79-Winter Term
    - Vol. 11 No. 02, 1979-10
    - Vol. 11 No. 03, undated [1979-1980]
    - Vol. 11 No. 04, undated [1979-1980]
  - 1980/81-1989/90
    - Vol. 12 No. 01, 1980-Spring
    - Vol. 12 No. 02, 1980-Summer
    - Vol. 12 No. 03, 1980-Autumn
    - Vol. 12 No. 04, 1981-Winter
    - Vol. 12 Special Report, undated [1980-1981]
    - Vol. 13 No. 01, 1981-Spring
    - Vol. 13 No. 02, 1981-Summer
    - Vol. 13 No. 03, 1981-Autumn
    - Vol. 13 No. 04, 1982-Winter
    - Vol. 14 No. 01, 1982-Spring
    - Vol. 14 No. 02, 1982-Summer
    - Vol. 14 No. 03, 1982-Fall
    - Vol. 14 No. 04, 1983-Winter
    - Vol. 15 No. 01, 1983-Spring
    - Vol. 15 No. 02, 1983-Summer
    - Vol. 16 No. 01, 1984-04
    - Vol. 16 No. 02, 1984-06
    - Vol. 16 No. 03, 1984-10
    - Vol. 16 No. 04, 1985-01
    - Vol. 17 No. 01, 1985-04
    - Vol. 17 No. 02, 1985-08
    - Vol. 17 No. 02?[3], 1985-08
      [This issue was printed with the incorrect date.]
    - Vol. 17 No. 04, 1985-12
    - Vol. 18 No. 01, 1986-03
    - Vol. 18 No. 02, 1986-06
    - Vol. 18 No. 03, 1986-08
    - Vol. 18 No. 04, 1986-10
    - Vol. 19 No. 01, 1987-02
    - Vol. 19 No. 02, 1987-04
    - Vol. 19 No. 03, 1987-06
    - Vol. 19 No. 04, 1987-10
    - Vol. 19 No. 05, 1987-12
    - Vol. 20 No. 01, 1988-02
    - Vol. 20 No. 02, 1988-04
    - Vol. 20 No. 03, 1988-06
    - Vol. 20 No. 04, 1988-08
    - Vol. 20 No. 05, 1988-10
    - Vol. 20 No. 06, 1988-12?
    - Vol. 21 No. 01, 1989-02
    - Vol. 21 No. 02, 1989-04
    - Vol. 21 No. 03, 1989-06
    - Vol. 21 No. 04, 1989-10
    - Vol. 21 No. 05, 1989-12
  - 1990-2000
    - Vol. 22 No. 01, 1990-02
    - Vol. 22 No. 02, 1990-04
    - Vol. 22 No. 03, 1990-06
    - Vol. 22 No. 04, 1990-10
    - Vol. 22 No. 05, 1990-12
    - Vol. 23 No. 01, 1991-02
    - Vol. 23 No. 02, 1991-05
    - Vol. 23 No. 03, 1991-10
    - Vol. 23 No. 04, 1991-12
    - Vol. 24 No. 01, 1992-02
    - Vol. 24 No. 02, 1992-06
    - Vol. 24 No. 03, 1992-10
    - Vol. 24 No. 04, 1992-12
    - Vol. 25 No. 01, 1993-03
    - Vol. 25 No. 02, 1993-06
    - Vol. 25 No. 03, 1993-10
    - Vol. 25 No. 04, 1993-12
    - Vol. 26 No. 01, 1994-03
    - Vol. 26 No. 02, 1994-06
    - Vol. 26 No. 03, 1994-10
    - Vol. 26 No. 04, 1994-12
    - Vol. 27 No. 01, 1995-03
    - Vol. 27 No. 02, 1995-06
    - Vol. 27 No. 03, 1995-10
    - Vol. 27 No. 04, 1995-12
    - Vol. 28 No. 01, 1996-03
    - Vol. 28 No. 02, 1996-06
    - Vol. 28 No. 03, 1996-09
    - Vol. 28 No. 04, 1996-Winter
    - Vol. 29 No. 01, 1997-Spring
    - Vol. 29 No. 02, 1997-Summer
    - Vol. 29 No. 03, 1997-Fall
    - Vol. 30 No. 01, 1998-Spring
    - Vol. 30 No. 02, 1998-Summer
    - Vol. 30 No. 03, 1998-Fall
    - Vol. 31 No. 01, 1999-Spring
    - Vol. 31 No. 02, 1999-Summer
    - Vol. 31 No. 03, 1999-Fall
  - 2000-2006
    - Vol. 32 No. 01, 2000-Spring
    - Vol. 32 No. 02, 2000-Summer
    - Vol. 32 No. 03, 2000-Fall
    - Vol. 33 No. 01, 2001-Winter
    - Vol. 33 No. 02, 2001-Summer
    - Vol. 33 No. 03, 2001-Fall
    - Vol. 34 No. 01, 2002-Spring
    - Vol. 34 No. 02, 2002-Summer
    - Vol. 34 No. 03, 2002-Fall
    - Vol. 35 No. 01, 2003-Winter
    - Vol. 35 No. 02, 2003-Summer
    - Vol. 35 No. 03, 2003-Fall
    - Vol. 36 No. 01, 2004-Spring
    - Vol. 36 No. 02, 2004-Summer
    - Vol. 36 No. 03, 2004-Fall
    - Vol. 37 No. 01, 2005-Fall
    - Vol. 38 No. 01, 2006-Spring
    - Vol. 38 No. 02, 2006-Summer
    - Vol. 38 No. 03, 2006-Fall
- Michigan Today: Online Edition 1993-current
  The Michigan Today: Online Edition series is the web delivered version of the printed magazine that first appeared in March 1993 and continues with the current web-only version. Initially the web version included only select parts of the printed magazine. Beginning in 2001, some unique content was created for the online version of Michigan Today. An "Alumnae/Alumni News" section was published exclusively in the online version of the magazine and a "Books" section was published with additional content in the online version of the publication. Beginning with the Winter 2007 issue, Michigan Today became a web-only publication. The current and archived back issues of the online Michigan Today is maintained by the University of Michigan News Service. The Michigan Today website provides both a chronological listing of issues and full text search capability.
  - Michigan Today website
- Michigan Today NewsE
  The Michigan Today: NewsE series represents the complete run of the electronic newsletter version of the publication published from December 2003 to July 2007. It is available as html through Deep Blue. The Deep Blue interface provides full text searching of all issues.
  - No.2003-08 August 2003
  - No.2003-09 September 2003
  - No.2003-10 October 2003
  - No.2003-11 November 2003
  - No.2003-12 December 2003
  - No.2004-01 January 2004
  - No.2004-02 February 2004
  - No.2004-04 April 2004
  - No.2004-05 May 2004
  - No.2004-06 June 2004
  - No.2004-08 August 2004
  - No.2004-09 September 2004
  - No.2004-10 October 2004
  - No.2004-12 December 2004
  - No.2005-01 January 2005
  - No.2005-02 February 2005
  - No.2005-03 March 2005
  - No.2005-04 April 2005
  - No.2005-05 May 2005
  - No.2005-06 June 2005
  - No.2005-07 July 2005
  - No.2005-09 September 2005
  - No.2005-10 October 2005
  - No.2005-11 November 2005
  - No.2006-01 January 2006
  - No.2006-02 February 2006
  - No.2006-03 March 2006
  - No.2006-04 April 2006
  - No.2006-05 May 2006
  - No.2006-06 June 2006
  - No.2006-07 July 2006
  - No.2006-08 August 2006
  - No.2006-09 September 2006
  - No.2006-10 October 2006
  - No.2006-11 November 2006
  - No.2007-01 January 2007
  - No.2007-02 February 2007
  - No.2007-03 March 2007
  - No.2007-04 April 2007
  - No.2007-05 May 2007
  - No.2007-06 June 2007
  - No.2007-07 July 2007
- Photographs 1984-2004
  The Photographs series consists of images collected during the research and editing process. The majority of these images are positive photographic prints; a small quantity of negatives, transparencies, and digital files are also included. The images document important research and innovations at the university, various aspects of university history, and important individuals within the university community. Most images have only minimal description including the photographer name, source of the image, or subject of the image. In some cases, several versions or variations of the same image are included.
  - October 1984 (Box 2)
  - January 1985 (Box 2)
  - April 1985 (Box 2)
  - October 1985 (Box 2)
  - December 1985 (Box 2)
  - March 1986 (Box 2)
  - August 1986 (Box 2)
  - October 1986 (Box 2)
  - February 1987 (Box 2)
  - April 1987 (Box 2)
  - June 1987 (Box 2)
  - October 1987 (Box 2)
  - December 1987 (Box 2)
  - February 1988 (Box 2)
  - April 1988 (Box 2)
  - June 1988 (Box 2)
  - August 1988 (Box 2)
  - October 1988 (Box 2)
  - December 1988 (Box 2)
  - February 1989 (Box 2)
  - April 1989 (Box 2)
  - June 1989 (Box 2)
  - October 1989 (Box 2)
  - December 1989 (Box 2)
  - February 1990 (Box 2)
  - April 1990 (Box 2)
  - June 1990 (Box 2)
  - October 1990 (Box 2)
  - December 1990 (Box 2)
  - February 1991 (Box 3)
  - October 1991 (Box 3)
  - December 1991 (Box 3)
  - June 1992 (Box 3)
  - October 1992 (Box 3)
  - December 1992 (Box 3)
  - October 1993 (Box 3)
  - December 1993 (Box 3)
  - March 1994, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - June 1995, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - June 1996, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Spring/Fall 1997, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - April 1998, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - September 1999, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Fall 2000, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - May 2001, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - June 2001 (Box 4)
  - Fall 2002 (Box 4)
  - June 2002 (Box 4)
  - December 2003 (Box 4)
  - Spring 2004 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Various Dates (Box 1)